What makes you cry?
是什么让你哭泣？
Being moved by a soppy or sad movie, waving a loved one off, or getting emotional after splitting up with your partner can all cause tears to roll down our faces.
被一部煽情或悲伤的电影打动、送别至亲之人、或是与伴侣分手后情绪激动，这些都可能让泪水从脸颊滑落。
We all have the power to cry, but is that a good thing?
我们每个人都有哭泣的本能，但哭泣究竟是不是一件好事呢？
When you think about it, shedding tears from your eyes is an odd thing to do.
仔细想想，从眼睛里流泪是一种很奇怪的行为。
But it seems to be an automatic reaction when we get sad, upset or even when we’re very happy.
但当我们悲伤、沮丧，甚至极度喜悦时，流泪似乎是一种本能反应。
What triggers this reaction differs from person to person. However, the feeling is the same – your cheeks puff up, your eyes tighten and before you know it, tears are streaming down your face.
触发这种反应的原因因人而异，但那种感受却是相通的——脸颊发胀，眼眶发紧，在你没意识到之前，泪水早已夺眶而出。
Some of us may sniffle a little while others might cry like a baby – and some people suggest that it’s women who cry more than men.
有些人可能只是抽抽搭搭，有些人却会号啕大哭——而且有人认为，女性比男性更爱哭。
A study in the UK in 2017 found that women admitted that they cry 72 times a year.
英国2017年的一项研究发现，女性承认自己一年会哭72次，平均来说，这一数字高于男性。
This was, on average, more than men.
亚当·卢瑟福在为英国广播公司撰写的文章中表示：“几乎所有相关研究都表明，女性确实比男性更爱哭，而且从我们开展研究以来，这个结论一直没有变过。”
Writing for the BBC, Adam Rutherford says “according to pretty much every study done, women do cry more than men, and this result has been consistent since we’ve been looking.”
但这是否意味着男性不如女性容易难过或情绪化？
But does this mean men don’t get as upset or emotional as women, or are they just more embarrassed about showing their true feelings?
还是说他们只是更羞于表露真实情绪？
The debate continues.
关于这个问题的争论仍在继续。
One place where we experience emotional and tearful outbursts is in the workplace.
职场是一个容易情绪爆发、催人落泪的地方。
This can be somewhere where emotions run high – someone might be stressed, their workload might be too much, and, as therapist, Joanna Cross told the BBC, “crying is often a build-up of frustration and undealt-with situations and it’s a bit of a final straw moment.”
这里有时会情绪高涨——有人可能压力山大，有人可能超负荷工作。正如心理咨询师乔安娜·克罗斯在接受英国广播公司采访时所说：“哭泣往往是挫败感不断累积、诸多问题悬而未决的结果，有点像压垮骆驼的最后一根稻草。”
She describes how someone might start weeping when they’re just asked to make a cup of tea because, “actually that’s often a backlog of situations.”
她还提到，有的人可能只是被要求泡杯茶，就突然哭了起来，因为“这通常是许多积压问题的总爆发”。
But crying in the office or elsewhere can be cathartic: it can actually make you feel better.
但无论是在办公室还是其他场合，哭泣都能起到宣泄情绪的作用：它其实能让你感觉好受一些。
Maybe it dissolves or clears the negative or sad feelings you’ve had.
或许哭泣能消解或驱散你心中的负面情绪和悲伤。
Bawling your eyes out shows others how you feel, so perhaps it’s a crying shame that more of us, particularly men, don’t cry more often.
放声大哭能让别人了解你的感受，所以，我们中更多人，尤其是男性，不常哭泣，这或许是件憾事。